I found myself lost and alone on this journey
Though my heart wandered far and wide, I could move not an inch
But now I can depart for any distant land
Now that we've met on this road
Even the unfamiliar songs of travelers
Can spark nostalgia in me when I'm with you
If the world we dreamed of exists somewhere,
Then let's go search for it beyond the wind
Through chilling dawns,
Through arid noons,
Through shivering nights,
Let's go see what lies at the end
Parti mis tuelo morow.
Lu spinzzio tilatto cul.
Thank you.
Same to you.
Thank you very much.
Well, then...
Um...
Where did you come to hear of this road?
At a recent stop in a Poroson tavern.
Didn't you hear the rumors about the wolves?
I did indeed.
But I'm in a hurry, so I decided to take the risk.
I see...
Is something the matter?
No... I mean...
Ask anything at all. Is there something you need?
Is there any way
that you could hire me?
Wolf and the Shepherd's Lamb
I'm a shepherd.
I can stave off wolves as well as care for sheep.
If you hire me, I can protect you from wolves during your journey.
Would you consider it?
Enek.
Wait just a moment while I ask my companion.
Her skills?
If she's skilled, she might be worth hiring.
You heard us, surely.
You already have me, do you not?
I know having you by my side is more than enough.
But it's never occurred to me to use a shepherd to drive off wolves.
There could be a new business in it.
Human males like to have as many females as possible, it seems.
I'm not being blinded by her charm.
You're much cuter than her, anyway.
I suppose that's a passing mark.
So, what of her skill?
I suppose she'd be in the high range.
Be a little more concrete.
I could take a sheep from her,
but ordinary wolves wouldn't stand a chance, even in packs.
Is that so?
She's very skilled at handling her dog.
The nastiest shepherds are the ones who have a clever dog that they share a strong bond with.
It looks to me like both those things are true of her.
Her voice suggests she's young, which means she'll get even nastier.
Perhaps I should do something about that...
All right, all right. Thanks.
Wait.
Are you really going to hire her?
I was planning to.
If you hire her, she will be accompanying us for a time, right?
You don't want to?
It's not that I do not want to.
Lubinheigen's only two days away.
Still no good?
Nor did I say that.
Sorry, but bear with it for a little while.
What am I supposed to bear?
Well, I mean...
Really, I only want to see how effective a shepherd is against wolves.
That's fine with me. You're the one who might have a problem.
What will you do if my identity is exposed while she's traveling with us?
I get it now.
You wanted me to say something like...
"I want to travel together, just the two of us."
Fool!
Sorry.
Geez.
Well, I doubt I'll be exposed in two days.
Do as you will.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Not at all!
So...
How does forty Trie for the trip to Lubinheigen sound?
With a bonus if we happen to be attacked by wolves but make it unharmed.
Is that not enough?
It's perfect. Thank you very much!
Likewise.
May I inquire as to your name?
Oh, I'm sorry.
N-Norah Arendt.
Enek!
Have you been a shepherd long?
No, just four years now.
I began my time as a shepherd when I first met him.
That's unusual.
And before that?
I helped at an almshouse attached to an abbey and in return was allowed to live there.
While I was relying on the almshouse, I'd always wanted to find a real trade of my own.
It was good fortune meeting Enek.
Your prayers were surely answered.
Yes, I can't help but think that I have God to thank for our meeting.
When I found him, he was in a sad state, covered in wounds.
From wolves?
No, probably from bandits or mercenaries.
He was cowering under an overhang on a hill with this staff in his mouth.
I see.
I must say, I never would have expected you to offer to escort me.
It's hardly a common thing for shepherds to do, is it?
Well...
I just
wanted to talk to someone.
I know that feeling.
And I actually want to become a seamstress,
but I need money to pay for the guild membership fees and such.
The way I see it,
you could make more money from guarding merchants than from herding sheep.
I bet it's hard to find unclaimed fields.
It is.
There are many shepherds in every safe area.
So all that's left are wolf-strewn fields, huh?
Yes.
Wolves sure can be a pain.
And they're clever and sly, too!
If I speak ill of them, they may hear, so...
Indeed.
I'm sorry for making you stop this early.
It's no problem. I know that shepherds have to get to sleep before the sun goes down.
I have to watch over the sheep throughout the night, so...
When I look at their wool, I always wonder what kind of clothing it'll be made into.
You do a remarkable job.
I'm very impressed.
You're flattering me.
You should be in charge of more sheep, judging from your skills.
No, it's only by God's blessings that I'm entrusted with even this many.
A huge flock... I just couldn't...
Your employer has no eye for skill.
Maybe it's time for a change?
No way. I couldn't possibly do that.
Apologies. We merchants tend to think about things based on loss and profit.
Um...
Yes?
Do people change their employers often?
It's normal, if one is unsatisfied with one's terms of employment.
Is that so?
Pardon me for asking, but might your employer be the Church?
It's just my merchant's intuition speaking.
Yes, I'm tending to the sheep of a Church pastor.
He's been very considerate to me as well.
I take back what I said.
Your wages may be low, but the Church will never cease to exist until God himself forsakes us.
You'll never be out of work, and you'll always have something to eat.
You're right.
God never said anything against doing work on the side, though.
When we arrive in Lubinheigen, I'll make sure to ask my fellow merchants whether they need a reliable escort.
Really? I'd really appreciate it!
Hard work, that.
Daily care of one's tail is important.
Oh, you meant the child.
Her name is Norah Arendt.
Hey!
Look, I did ask for your approval.
Can't even relax and groom my tail.
Why couldn't you have done it in here?
If I'd done it in here...
If you did it here... what?
You certainly seemed to enjoy your chat with her.
With Norah?
Who else would I be talking about? The dog and sheep?
She wanted to talk. I didn't have any reason to refuse, did I?
It's been a while since I had a real conversation with a normal girl.
You couldn't even tell that she was uncomfortable speaking with you?
Well, that's okay.
If it was love at first sight, I wouldn't have the pleasure of seeing her fall for me.
What do you think? Aren't I quite the smooth talker?
It doesn't fit you! It doesn't fit you at all!
You don't have to laugh so hard.
Geez.
It's hilarious!
Are you done yet?
Yes, that's quite an ace you had up your sleeve.
Well, if your bad mood is gone, that's all that matters.
Yes, it all seems so trivial now.
It's like it was a gift from the child herself.
Good morning.
Nice to see you again.
That's it.
Thanks.
Thanks, as always.
You saved me a lot of trouble.
It would have taken ten times as long to obtain transit documents if we had to sit through routine inspections.
It's a benefit of being employed by the Church.
Here's forty Trie, as promised.
But if I exchange these silver coins, won't it come out to forty-five?
Call it an investment by a greedy merchant.
Investment?
Now that I know such a skilled shepherd, I might come across an opportunity to turn a profit on wool sometime.
Thank you very much.
We'll be staying at the trading house of the Lohen Trading Union.
Make sure you stop by before you head out to the fields with your sheep.
I may be able to introduce you to a few merchants in need of security.
Thank you very much.
By the way, do you have to stay on the path we traveled on?
No, I'm allowed to move to Kasrata, Poroson, and even Lamtra.
Lamtra?
Are you talking about...
Yes.
You don't travel on the roundabout official route, do you?
I take the shortcut through the forest, of course.
That eerie forest makes even the bravest of knights blanch.
I have no worries as long as I'm with Enek.
I daresay you'll have plenty of business, then.
I look forward to it.
The entrance for livestock is that way, so I'll excuse myself.
All that's left to do now is go through customs
and head to Lemerio Trading to sell the armor that we obtained thanks to you.
We're also going to buy peaches preserved in honey with what we earn.
Time to get a move on.
Hey, don't ignore me!
We can't buy any if they aren't selling any.
Chances are they won't have it, you know.
I know.
Don't make a fuss if they don't.
I'll do just that.
I told you...
What's that?
It prevents enemies from entering during times of war.
They use those holes to pour scalding oil on the enemy.
This is more of a castle than a city.
Letter of transit?
From Poroson?
What are you carrying?
Twenty sets of armor.
Armor from Poroson?
Yes, I purchased them wholesale from Latparon Trading. Is something wrong?
Well, all right.
How will you pay the taxes? Cash or goods?
Oh, with goods.
That's a wise decision.
Hand over two sets right over there.
Is it that rare to make a wholesale purchase from Poroson?
Not in my experience.
It's quite the contrary.
Here you go.
You may pass.
Bureaucrats will always be unpleasant people regardless of where you are.
Didn't you notice?
That civil servant scoffed at you.
After seeing our pile of armor, he probably thought,
"Don't act so high and mighty just because you're making money."
I don't care what he thought. We were able to enter town without a hassle.
Let's park our wagon and head to the market.
Good morning.
Do you now understand?
That hit the spot! Sir, one more!
One beer coming up. You sure can hold your liquor, young lady!
I've barely started!
You've fallen for one who loves to spend money, but she's a real beauty.
She'd be perfect if she didn't have a tail.
The liquor is good and the people lively. 'Tis a good city, no?
The liveliness comes at a price.
Watch yourselves around knights or mercenaries, okay?
A quarrel with them means a world of trouble.
Here you go.
You can count on me!
Where are we going now?
The trading house.
Wait up. You have froth on the side of your mouth.
Hey!
Geez!
Still...
Why must you drag me along to this trading house with you?
It's too dangerous to leave you alone.
It's true. I am a bit too lovely to be left unattended!
Not quite what I meant.
What if you get drunk and let your ears or tail show?
I'd just grab you in my jaws, and we'd dash from the city.
I can surely leap over those walls.
Isn't there an old tale about a knight and a girl like that?
The one where the knight carries the captive girl to safety?
That's the one!
Unlike the story, there's not a trace of romance in the idea of being carried away in a wolf's jaws.
Forget it. No way.
You aren't the sort that would look good getting rescued anyway.
By the way,
what is a trading house?
Risk and accidents go hand in hand with business,
and there's no one who will protect you from either one.
Just as knights wear armor,
we merchants protect ourselves by banding together.
Where we're going is a branch office of merchants who share the same birthplace.
This always brings me back!
All of the buildings in my hometown look like this.
It must be nice to have your home scattered across the land.
Stay here while I take care of business.
What? Are you not going to bring me in and brag about how lucky you are to your countrymen?
I'll be done before you know it. If you wait nicely, I'll buy you some sweetbread.
Don't treat me like a child!
You don't want any?
Of course I do.
What are you doing here, you sad excuse of a merchant?
Wandering around here at this hour... Cares not a whit for making money...
You'd be better off as a thief!
Great merchants earn their money without having to soil their shoes.
The only stain is the ink upon their fingers.
Running around the market all day is the sign of a third-rate merchant.
Am I wrong?
You've found yourself a way with words.
Welcome back, my son!
Please stop the "my son" nonsense.
What are you saying? All in the Lohen Trading Union are my sons and daughters.
I even know of all the times you wet your bedroll after we made camp.
Or should I mention the time you and your friends stole money and snuck off to the brothel, scared shitless?
All right! All right!
Did a man called Lawrence come by?
Lawrence? I haven't even seen a mouse these past few days.
I see.
Next Episode: "Wolf and Conspiracies."